

Full-stack developer with expertise in AWS, application architecture design, DevOps and team management. Specialized in building web applications with React and Node.js that are written in TypeScript and deployed to Docker or Kubernetes environments using CI/CD pipelines.

Email

manuel.henke@yahoo.de

LinkedIn

<u>linkedin.com/in/manuel-henke</u>

Phone

+49 1517 0360 717

Website

henkebyte.com

Work Experience

GT-ARC (TU Berlin)

Jul 2023 - Oct 2024

Team Lead: Platform & Applications

Oct 2023 - Oct 2024

I was leading a small team of developers to build a data platform as distributed system for our automated vehicles and road infrastructure using Kafka, Postgres and Python. While participating in application development, I was the Tech Lead, Product Owner and responsible for the deployment to Kubernetes/Docker environments via GitLab pipelines that I introduced.

Researcher & Software Developer

Jul 2023 - Oct 2024

My research focused on Cooperative, Connected and Automated Mobility (CCAM) alongside the BeIntelli project. I was responsible for developing web applications to make automated driving tangible. These applications were built using TypeScript, React, Mapbox, MUI, Express.js, Socket.IO, and Prisma.

OEV Online Dienste

Dec 2019 - May 2023

Fullstack-Developer (Working Student)

During my employment, I have been part of various SCRUM-based teams building:

- WordPress web application (PHP) with serverless backend functionality written in Java
- Alexa Skill with serverless backend services (JS)
- Multi-tenant Web Components library (TS)
- Corporate web application using TypeScript, React, Fastify, MongoDB, Keycloak, Kubernetes/Helm

In these projects, Jira and Confluence were used for documentation and issue tracking. Most of the applications are deployed to the AWS cloud using GitHub Actions or AWS CodePipeline. My role has been that of an all-rounder, working on application architecture, front-end and back-end development, database schema and CI/CD pipelines.

VKB

Jun 2018 - Nov 2019

Software Developer (Working Student)

I was part of a small team that developed a WordPress-based web shop application for internal use. It was built with PHP, including a WordPress theme and several WordPress plugins. The application was powered with microservices written in Java. The frontend leveraged libraries like Bootstrap and jQuery.

Education

Technical University of Berlin 2016 - 2023

M.Sc. - Information Systems Management (1.3) 2020 - 2023

Thesis: "Implementation of a use case mapper for CCAM based mobility solutions in the platform economy framework" (1.0)

B.Sc. - Information Systems Management (1.9) 2016 - 2020

Thesis: "Design and development of a cloud-based solution approach for automated home accessibility assessment as an iOS app" (1.0)

Languages

German	English
Native	Proficient

Skills

JavaScript/TypeScript	•••••
React	•••••
HTML, CSS	•••••
Vue.js	••••
Docker	••••
Java	••••
Swift	•••00
Kubernetes	•••00
SQL	•••00
Python	••000
PHP	••000

Interests

Cycling, Open-Source Development, Traveling